hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and we're back and
listen I know we had an episode last
week but I'll tell you this my second
born son was born on Tuesday at 5 in the
morning and I I feel like a new man a
new person um like I have been
transformed and
rebirthed like in the hero's
journey sort of we talk about the hero's
journey all the time here in marketing
and storytelling but I feel like I've
gone through my own sort of Heroes
Journey since
Tuesday um and come out the other side
and and and I am rejoicing and thankful
that I'm here with you right now
recording this Saturday night um we just
put the baby down both babies down cuz
we got two now right and so everything's
good got a little bit of a window to
record this and that's what I want to
talk about today is I want to talk about
your productivity
and how to get stuff done when you don't
have a lot of time this is something I
noticed that a lot of people deal with a
lot of people experience in their
businesses a lot of people experience in
their in their life is they have a job
that they're working or they have um
kids or situations and stuff like that
that they're dealing with we all got
stuff we all got
situations and it's how we can make the
most of those that really determines our
success you know as business owners
most of the time when we're starting our
business we're not going Allin where
it's like our only main thing that we're
doing and we have other things that
we're doing that produce income
throughout my business I've constantly
maintained other Consulting contracts
that have paid me multiple six and even
seven figures that take up a good
portion of my time even when I was
building my coaching business we're
solely focused on what I do in my
coaching business here at Jeremiah
Kowski decom and I love helping people
with this to be able to to reach their
goals as coaches and Consultants as well
as course
creators what you got to learn how to do
is get the most out of every day that
you have and this isn't about working a
ton of hours because a lot of times we
don't have a lot of hours to work we
don't have extra hours we got to learn
to get the most of the time that we have
and so that's what I want to talk about
here for me I found myself that when I
have a lot of time I end up evaporating
a lot of that time away because because
I end up overthinking and I end up
coming up with reasons why um I I need
to do this I need to focus on this this
isn't ready yet I I got to I got to
spend all this time perfecting
everything and that's not helping us and
then what I find is is I have weeks like
I had this week where I literally have
had no time I mean I I I have not had a
this probably been the the least amount
of time that I've had all week and guess
guess what for some reason my
productivity has skyrocketed this week I
often find this to be the theory of
constraints at play here when we apply a
artificial constraint of some kind that
tightens things up we end up by
necessity with the bottleneck having to
create some sort of a system to speed
those bottlenecks up and so bottlenecks
can actually be a good thing sometimes
we have this belief that if I just
removed all the bottlenecks everything
would be much easier for me that's not
true because I can tell you this as
somebody who has lived that life where I
had zero bottlenecks removed and I have
multiple bottlenecks I can actually tell
you that by having the bottlenecks is
when I was the most productive and made
the most amount of money and then what I
did was I was able to systematize those
things I was able to learn how to
delegate those things as well but this
goes beyond just delegation it goes into
learning how to do things quicker not
taking a ton of time thinking about or
processing or coming up with reasons why
you need to do this or or or processing
through what you're feeling emotionally
before you take action on things rather
just doing the thing that you need to do
right when you need to do it or later
when you have time to do it and not
diling around or dallying along it's
about getting the job done and doing
those things and again you might not
want to hear that and I understand that
but stick with me in this podcast
because I want to explain this to I
resisted this for the longest time this
goes beyond just discipline it goes into
the fact that sometimes we create habits
where we think that things need to take
longer than they really need to and the
words that we use the way that we talk
to ourselves about ourselves to other
people about the stuff that we need to
accomplish that we want to accomplish
that we want to get done are actually
some of the root reasons why we're
struggling to accomplish those things I
remember myself I look back and I would
say well I I need this much time to get
these things done the reason why I'm not
getting them done is because I don't
have that much time and how many of you
have found yourself maybe using some of
that same language about how you talk
about yourself in your own business or
your own processes and so we have to
look at how are we talking about what we
have time for what are our beliefs about
the time that we have and then making a
decision to say you know what I'm going
to pretend like I'm playing a little
video game here this is what I had to do
for my myself and I want to see if I can
get the same amount of stuff done in the
shortest amount of time
possible and this is something that
actually my wife encouraged me with
because she knows that every time I do
this two things I resist it pretty
strongly I don't like it because I like
to just relax and take my time and I
have like a like a spa lifestyle I'm
just like oh it's so
peaceful that's how I like to do things
that's how I prefer to do stuff 100%
but life doesn't often throw us those
abilities and those
opportunities and so what we have to
learn how to do is we have to learn how
to actually have find that inner peace
inside of us while doing things as
efficiently as possible so if I know
that something is going to take me an
hour to do how can I maybe see if I can
get the same thing done in 30 minutes
with the same level of quality the same
output as far as that goes what are some
of those things that I can do that can
help accelerate me in that level and
this might take some practice this might
take some time you might literally get a
get a headache and start to feel
nauseous even thinking about this I did
and unfortunately it created a lot of
tension and anxiety for me especially
this last week having the newborn baby
was a great example of this and I just
had to realize you know what I'm going
to just take it one day at a time if I
don't get certain things done that's
okay we're going to take it one day at a
time
keep moving
forward that's one of the things that
I've been saying since the beginning of
this podcast episode is just keep moving
forward what are those things that you
need to do to keep making forward
momentum forward progress you you missed
a deadline move it up a couple of days
and then hit that deadline you missed it
again move it up another couple of days
and then hit that deadline instead of
beating yourself up give yourself some
self-compassion and some selflove
internally around what you know know
that you can do and what you need to do
listen one of the biggest reasons why we
struggle is we are way too stinking hard
on ourselves about what we think that we
should be doing what a person like us if
we were successful would be doing and
instead if we just gave ourselves a
little bit of that Grace it actually
becomes a lot easier find the joy in the
tension that's another strategy right
there is finding happiness in the crappy
situations in the horrible schedule in
the lack of sleep because the toddler is
waking you up in the middle of the night
can I tell you this if you can find joy
in the toughest of
situations everything else becomes a lot
easier then you figure out okay how can
I get stuff done I got a limited amount
of time I got a small window of time
what can I get done in that time I'll
tell you what I did today and I'm going
to give you it's just like today was my
ultimate like best day so far uh this
podcast right here I had a little bit of
time I'm recording the podcast I had a
little bit of time when both of the
babies were down for a nap I literally
wrote an entire sales letter and created
a landing page in fact I want to show
that to you here right now if you're on
the video version of this uh podcast I'm
going to P I'm going to pull it up and
I'm going to show you exactly what it
looks like I was working with one of my
clients and I was able to build out uh a
a landing page right here uh for this
for a for a training that we're putting
together during nap time I was able to
write this sales copy and literally
build build out this landing page in a
half hour from zero from scratch and
it's ready to go once we add in the the
optin form and that's exactly what I'm
talking about is for you in your
business instead of taking hours or days
previously that would have taken me 3
days to get the progress up to this
point of where this is to show this to a
client well guess
what took me 30 minutes because that's
how much time I gave myself and that's
how long I decided and chose for it to
take me you know often times we look at
content creation we look at our landing
pages we look at our process that we
need to do in our business we look at
videos that we need to create and we
come up with reasons why we can't do it
why it's going to take us a lot longer
why it needs to take us a lot longer and
we can't get it done as quickly as we
want it to but can I tell you this it
doesn't have to be that way you can
accomplish far more than you've ever
imagined with the time that you had
often times we are programmed to believe
that something needs to take a certain
amount of time or that it's not worth it
that we're not giving enough Excellence
if it's not taking a longer amount of
time and then we get burnt out and then
it ends up being a year or two years and
we haven't launched our program we
haven't launched our offer yet we
haven't put something out there because
it's not perfect enough and that's one
of the biggest messages if I can get
that across to as many people as
possible is we got to to kill this
perfectionism thing it's not helping us
I think it's a great spirit of
Excellence that has gone overboard and
we need to brain it in and we need to
tell it that it's not the way that we're
functioning we need to say thank you for
trying to help us do things great and
not mess stuff up but we're going to go
from here and we're going to do our very
best with the resources that we have
with the time that we have to accomplish
things to the best of our ability and
accept whatever outcome happens whatever
result comes out of it and so at the end
of the day if you are a coach Mentor
trainer consultant you've been trying to
scale your business you've been trying
to get more clients you trying to get
people to buy from you you got to give
up this thing that says that it has to
take a lot of time and figure out how
can I take one thing this week and
accomplish it in onethird the amount of
time that I normally would give myself
to do this challenge yourself in this
and you might just be shocked as to what
happens listen if you're a coach Mentor
consultant I'd love to work with you and
I'd love to come alongside you to help
you get more results in your business
that's why we have my client growth
accelerator program is to create an
environment and an atmosphere that gets
results not just Theory not just another
program where you're not going to get
anything from it but actually turning
your vision into something that makes
you money and produces the results that
you want in your business so I'd love to
see you in my client growth accelerator
program make sure to jump in there and
also make sure to check out some of the
new free classes that we have over my
website about starting your business
about running Facebook ads we'll talk
soon grow your life everybody have a
good one
[Music]
[Applause]